Guide to the Walter Metzger American Association of University Professors Records of Academic Freedom and Tenure, 1888-2009 MS2369
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- AAUP Academic Freedom and Tenure, 1888-2009; Series 2
  - AAUP Committees and Committee Policies, 1922-2009; Series 2 Subseries 3
    - AAUP Policy: Academic Freedom and Electronic Policy, 1997-1998; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - AAUP Policy: Non Disclosure, 1958-1962; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - AAUP Policy: "Communist Cases"- Quest for National Security, 1956-1958; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - AAUP Policy: Loyalty Oaths, 1950-1990; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Substance Abuse, 1990-1992; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Academic Governance General, 1954-1992; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - History of Academic Governance, 1945-1993; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Trustees and Presidents, 1950-1991; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Bibliography- Academic Presidents, 1980-1995; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Delocalization, 1972-1987; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Bureaucracy in Higher Education, 1966-1968; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Scientific Management, 1976-1991; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Faculty on Boards, February 1967; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Public- Private, 1984-1987; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Marketing, 1981-1984; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Columbia Senate, 1968-1974; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Faculty Power, 1959-1989; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Students in Academic Governance, 1968-1969; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Grading, 1993; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - AAUP Policy: Committee T, 1981-1984; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - AAUP Policy: Committee T, 1940-1992; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - AAUP Policy: Divestment, 1971-1991; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - AAUP Policy: FBI, CIA, and Academic Freedom, 1955-1988; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - AAUP Policy: Secret Research, 1968-1984; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - AUP Policy: Freedom of Information Act, 1968-1984; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Restricted Gifts, 1976-1991; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - AAUP Policy: Business Subsides For Research, 1978-2000; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - AAUP Policy: Research Conflict of Interest, December 13, 1989; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - AAUP Policy: Research on Human Subjects (IRB), 1975-1989; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Artistic Freedom, 1985-1994; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - AAUP: Secret Defense Research Classified Research, 1967-1991; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - AAUP Policy: Animal Rights, 1937-1990; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Fraud in Science, July 13, 1996; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Intellectual Property, May/June 1998; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Board- Journal Higher Education, 1974-1994; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - AAUP Attitude Towards Unions- Historical, 1938-1968; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - General- Collective Bargaining, 1967-1988; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - AAUP Decision Toenter Collective Bargaining (1 of 2), 1970-1983; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - AAUP Decision Toenter Collective Bargaining, 1962-1972; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Collective Bargaining and Academic Freedom, 1971-1989; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Collective Bargaining and Unit Determination, 1972-1985; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Collective Bargaining and Academic Tenure, 1973-1974; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Bibliography and Research- Collective Bargaining, 1974-1987; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Box Score and Trends in Collective Bargaining, 1973-1988; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Collective Bargaining and Scope of Bargaining, 1976-1985; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - AAUP on Strikes (1 of 2), 1966-1975; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - AAUP on Strikes (2 of 2), 1966-1990; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Collective Bargaining and Salaries, 1974-1984; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Collective Bargaining and Salaries, 1976-1978; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Collective Bargaining and Governance, 1971-1976; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Collective Bargaining and Exclusivity, 1975; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Collective Bargaining and Agency Shop, 1970-1982; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - AAUP Relations- AFT, NEA, 1975-1987; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - AAUP Organizing Record, 1974-1983; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Teaching Assistants and Collective Bargaining, 1997-2000; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - General- Collective Bargaining Contract, 1972-1984; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - General- Collective Bargaining Laws, 1976-1986; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Financial Exigency and Collective Bargaining, 1975-1984; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - AAUP Policy: Faculty Honoring Picket-Lines, June 19, 1978; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Permanent Replacement, 1993-1994; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Collective Bargaining and Arbitration, 1975-1998; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Yeshiva Case, 1975-1998; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - AAUP Policy: Rou Relations, Federal Government, November 10, 1960; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - AAUP Policy: Committee R, 1978-1991; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Policy: AAUP Merger (1 of 2), 1974-1991; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Policy: AAUP Merger (2 of 2), 1979-1981; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Committee Z, 1996-2008; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - AAUP Election, 1995-1996; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Vernon Snow- Retired Professor Data Files, 1985; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - AAUP Policy: Status Part- Time Faculty (1 of 2), 1964-1987; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - AAUP Policy: Status Part- Time Faculty (2 of 2), 1976-2000; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Committee A Meeting Agenda, June 2009; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Committee A Membership Lists, 1961-2000; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Committee A Agendas, 1991-1997; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Committee A Agendas, 1970-1979; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Committee A Agendas, 1958-1969; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - AAUP Policy: Faculty Work-load, 1970; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - AAUP Policy: Conditions of Work, May 9, 1961; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Sabbatical, October 15, 1993; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - AAUP Policy: Teaching and Research, 1961-1972; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - AAUP Policy: Forced Contribution to TIAA, 1975-1976; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - AAUP Policy: TIAA Pensions, 1982-1984; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Academic Retirement Issues, 1978-1990; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Decentralization of Committee A Activities, 1968-1979; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - AAUP Policy: Due Process, 1954-1971; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - AAUP Policy: Trustee- FAC Discipline, 1973-1975; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Columbia- Grievance, January 1970; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - AAUP Policy: Arbitration in Lieu of Peer Review, 1973-1991; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - AAUP Policy: Retirement, Pensions, and Development of Policies, 1941-1984; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Financial Exigency, 1974-1992; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - AAUP Policy: Financial Exigency- External Relations, 1971-1986; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - AAUP Policy: Financial Exigency- Internal Debate, 1969-1990; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - AAUP Policy: Program Discontinuance, 1974-1998; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Financial Exigency and the Law, 1996; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - AAUP Policy: Resignations, 1929-1963; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - AAUP Policy: Salary Cuts and Other Sanctions, 1991-1992; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Grounds for Non- Renewal and Denial of Tenure Promotion, 1992-1995; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - AAUP Policy: Colleague, 1998-1999; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - AAUP Policy: Grounds for Dismissal, 1965-1998; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Mass Firings, 1998; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - AAUP Policy: Notice, 1959-1982; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - AAUP Policy: Prior Service, 1975-1986; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - AAUP Policy: Excessive Probation, 1964-2000; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Professional Ethics- General, 1961-1990; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Faculty Ethical Issues, 1964-1989; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Research Ethical Issues, 1976-1991; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - AAUP Policy: Faculty Ethical Issues- Early History, 1923-1929; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - AAUP Policy: Professional Ethics Code, 1957-1972; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - AAUP Policy: Faculty Responsibility Code, 1971; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - AAUP Policy: Academic Freedom and Course Grades, 1984; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Committee A Freedom to Teach Courses on Sexual Education, September 13, 1989; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - AAUP Policy: Fundamentalism, 1922-1923; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - AAUP Policy: Accuracy in Academia and Other External Pressure Groups, 1982-1987; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - AAUP Policy: Tenure and the Uncapping of Mandatory Retirement (1 of 2), 1963-1990; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - AAUP Policy: Tenure and the Uncapping of Mandatory Retirement (2 of 2), 1968-1989; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Schism in the Church, undated; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - AAUP Policy: Tenure Clock and Parenting, 1988-1989; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - AAUP Policy: Status of Librarians, 1977-1981; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - AAUP and Post-Tenure Review Revisited, 1996-1998; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Post-Tenure Review- Recent Statements, 1985-1997; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Wingspread: Post-Tenure Review, 1960-1989; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - "Professor of Practice", 1980-1995; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - AAUP Policy: Tenure in Law Schools, 1996; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - AAUP Policy: Scholar's Priviledge, 1972-1973; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - AAUP Policy: Award of Tenure as Judicial Remedy, 1980-1987; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - AAUP Policy: Faculty Contracts, 1967; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - AAUP Policy: Faculty Liability, 1982-1984; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - AAUP Policy: Status of Faculty Handbooks, October 2, 1985; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Access to Files, 1992-1999; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - AAUP Policy: Tenure of AAUP Staff, November 17, 1995; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - AAUP Policy: Locus of Tenure, 1985-1986; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Non- Tenure Tracks, 1973-1986; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - AAUP Policy: Tenure Quotas, 1973-1978; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - AAUP Policy: Tenure Excluded Personnel, 1964-1992; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Texts of 1915, 1925, 1940, 1950, and 1958 Statements, 1922-1992; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - AAUP Policy: Written Reasons, 1969-1971; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - AAUP Policy: Tenure in Medical Schools, 1982-1999; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 43, Folder 2)
- Drafts and Published Materials, 1915-2006; Series 3
  This series contains the drafts of published materials, reviews, speeches, and notes of Walter Metzger and his colleagues on Academic Freedom and Tenure. These files are dated from 1915- 2006.
  This series is divided into 3 subseries: Published Articles and Books, Reviews and Public Speeches, and Drafts and Notes.
  - Published Articles and Books, 1945-2006; Series 3 Subseries 1
    This subseries contains published articles and bibliographies of Walter Metzger and his colleague's work on Academic Freedom and Tenure. The files are dated 1945-2006.
    - "Action Through Correspondence": Progressive Education, January 1945; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Mosse, Brown, Metzger- Outline and Sources for History of Western Civilization, 1948; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Ideology and Intellectual: A Study of Thorstein Veblen, Philosophy of Science, April 1949; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - "Professors and Big Businessmen" PhD Dissertation, 1976-1977; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - College Professors and Big Business Men: A Study of American Ideologies 1860-1915, June 1950; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - American Social Thought, 1950-1953; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - "Some Perspectives on History of Academic Freedom": Antioch Review, 1953-1958; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Development of Academic Freedom: C.U. Press, 1953-1960; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - "German Contribution to American Theory of Academic Freedom": AAUP Bulletin, 1955; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Youth Conformity, 1960-1964; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "The First Investigation": AAUP Bulletin, 1961-1962; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - "Institutional Setting of Academic Freedom": Threshold Academic Careers, April 27-28, 1962; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Generalization About National Character, 1958-1967; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Expansion and Profession, June 1964; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Introduction to US Higher Education: Fulbright Scholars, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Academic Freedom in De-Localized Institutions, 1967-1996; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - New York Times: "Education Supplement'", 1970-1971; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Institutional Neutrality, 1970-1972; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Metzger- Boerstedt "Academic Tenure": Civil Liberties, 1972-1974; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - "Governance and Structure": Directions in Higher Education, Salem College, May 1972; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Whiche- Public Challenge, 1971-1972; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - History of Academic Tenure- Keast, Faculty Tenure, 1972-1973; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - "From Course to Institute": Dialogue USIA, 1973-1974; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - "What is a Profession", 1975-1980; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Editor, Academic Profession, Arnos, 1975-1976; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Academic Freedom and Scientific Freedom- MIT, Harvard- Daedalus, 1977-1980; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Historians and Academic Research- Studying Faculties, Blackburn, Editor, 1977-1978; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - History of Tenure: Current Issues in Higher Education AAHE, 1979; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - "Academic Freedom Today": Symposium- NYU Education Quarterly, 1981-1982; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Academic Profession- Bellacio, 1983-1987; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Fuchs and Himstead": Academe, 1986-1987; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - "Teaching and Research": Currents, 1987; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - "The Spectre of Anti- Professionism": AERA, 1987; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Profession and Constitution, 1988-2006; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Governance in Evolutionary Perspective, Governing Tomorrows Campus, Shustered, 1988-1989; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - History of 1940 Statement": Law and Contemporary Problems, 1963-1991; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Tulane Legal Conference, 1992; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Article: Critics of Academic Curriculum, 1995-1996; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - "A Stroll Along New Frontiers": University of Michigan, 1994-1998; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Academic Freedom and Scientific Freedom, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - My Writing on Victimization, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Walter's Bibliography, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Reviews and Speeches, 1950-2000; Series 3 Subseries 2
    This subseries contains article and book reviews on Academic Freedom and Tenure and speeches given at various universities by Walter Metzger. The files are dated from 1950-2000.
    - David Riesman: "Thorstein Veblen" Political Science Quarterly, 1950-1954; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Russell Kirk: "Academic Freedom" Political Science Quarterly, 1955-1956; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Charles A. Beard: "Economic Interpretation" Chicago Law Review, 1956; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Carl Bode "Anatomy of Popular Culture" New Leader, 1959-1987; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Caplow: "Academic Marketplace" American Sociological Review, 1958-1959; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Harold Hyman: "To Try Men's Souls" PSQ, 1959-1961; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Markham: "Noblest Cry" AHR, 1966; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Edgar Furniss: "Graduate School of Yale" AHR, 1965-1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Book Review: Philanthropy, Higher Education, Curti and Nash, History of Education Quarterly, 1966; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Book Review: Harper's University by Richard Stork, Harvard Educational Review, 1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Book Review: Mr. Justice Murphy, J. Woodford Howard, AHR, February 1970; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Book Review: Summerscale TC Record, 1970-1972; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Book Review: Rainsford, Congress and Higher Education, 1972-1975; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Book Review: Lipset, Ladd "Divided Academy", Science, 1975-1976; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Book Review: Saunder's Cold War, 1979- 1980; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Book Review: Sindler, Baake Academe, 1979-1980; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Testimony: Post-Tenure Review, 1969-1982; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Book Review: Burke Collegiate Populations, 1982-1984; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Book Review: Milton Eisenhower, 1983-1984; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Review: Geiger- Spencer Foundation, August 7, 1985; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Book Review: "Educating Republicans" David Robson, JEH, 1983-1986; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Book Review: "Weimar Professors" JHE, 1986-1987; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - Book Review: "New School for Social Research" New York History, 1986-1987; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Review: Herbert Proposal- Spencer Foundation, 1988; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Book Review, Science: "Stalking the Academic Communist" (Holmes), 1989; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - Review, Herbert: Pedagogica Historica, 1982-1989; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 48, Folder 26)
    - Review: Rudy, WWI and II- JHE, 1991-1992; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Review: Lionel Lewis - Lattimore, 1991; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Letter to Tom Haskell- Two Professions, August 12, 1993; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Russell: Academic Freedom- Academe, 1993; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Review: Ehrenberg ed. University, April 4, 1996; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Review: Riccards' College Board, 2006; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Reviews for Encyclopedias, 1970-1984; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Unpublished Reviews for Book Publishers, 1954-1996; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Unpublished Reviews for Journal Higher Education, 1968-1986; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Testimony: Green Committee- House of Representatives, 1969; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Two Professions- Carol, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Speech: Historian Looks at National Character- Faculty Seminar, 1959; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Speech: Hero in America, 1965; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Speech: Governance (Senate) at Columbia, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Speeches on Carnegie Commission Report, 1974; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Speech: Bakke to Mellon Society, September 1978; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Speech: History and Social Sciences, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Speech: Spectre Is Haunting...Professionalism, 1983-1987; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Speech: Spectre is Haunting...Professionism (2 of 2), 1986-1987; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Speech: Dual Professional Loyalties, 1986; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Arlock on Curriculum- Rochester, 1992-1995; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Jews in Academic Profession- Israel, 1994-1995; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Speech on Academic Freedom at Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1993-1994; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Speech on Academic Freedom- Albany, 1999-2000; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Alaska- Academic Freedom, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Speeches on the 1940 Statement, 1978-1986; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Speeches on Academic Freedom, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Speech: Asymmetrical Reactions, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Collective Bargaining Talks, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Speech: Committee A in Action, 1988; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Speech: Conceptual Foundations and History of Academic Tenure, 1979; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Speeches: The Family, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 51, Folder 6)